[SPEAKER_00]: Look, for example, so when it comes to precepts, you know, whether something is... whether something is under allowance or not...
[SPEAKER_00]: Yes, you have the, you know, the broad definition.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could, you could take it in an even more specific manner.
[SPEAKER_00]: Say, like, well, like the precept for entertainment or similar.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it's like, oh, I shouldn't watch news.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or you could say, well, that's not necessarily specified.
[SPEAKER_00]: I could watch news.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's pretty much what differentiates whether you're just keeping the precepts or are you trying to train your mind through the precepts.
[SPEAKER_00]: So,
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not to say that watching the news is always bad, or always against the precepts, but it's to say that you can't use an external definition, however specific, developed, accurate, as a measure for the intentions that come from your own mind, which is what should be a reference point.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's like, um...
[SPEAKER_00]: Keeping the five precepts, keeping the eight precepts, and then say, I'm not watching the news, because I take that to mean the precept against entertainment.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's fine, but it still might not necessarily mean you're training your mind rightly.
[SPEAKER_00]: You just added more observances to the precepts.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it's like... that doesn't mean you should go and watch the news, but it means basically you need to recognize that the sole purpose of precepts broadly defined, more specifically defined, adding more observances to the precepts, all of that should be serving the same purpose of discerning your own intentions.
[SPEAKER_00]: As a reference point.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, that becomes the guiding criteria whether you should watch the news or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, why?
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, what's my current, right now, this living motivation to check the news?
[SPEAKER_00]: There might be some, I don't know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Practical reason and intention rooted in that reason, that's not necessarily coming out of, you know, entertainment or distraction.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or it might not be.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's what you always...
[SPEAKER_00]: The sole point is to be... to kind of direct you towards revealing that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Everybody knows their intentions.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's more like whether they have trained enough to just admit to themselves what those intentions are.
[SPEAKER_00]: Intentions cannot be...
[SPEAKER_00]: Intentions cannot be unconscious.
[SPEAKER_00]: Can it be, like, hidden in plain sight or something?
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they are the guiding principle for your action, whether you admit it, whether a person recognizes it or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: They are the force behind any action, any karma, anything that you're committing to.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it's not a question of...
[SPEAKER_00]: Revealing the mystery of where my intentions are and whether I can see it or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: You're just sitting down with yourself and, and like, admitting, hold on, why?
[SPEAKER_00]: Just asking a question.
[SPEAKER_00]: Why do I watch?
[SPEAKER_00]: Why do I want to, like, say, watch the news or read the newspapers?
[SPEAKER_00]: Right here, right now.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not yesterday, not tomorrow, not because, well, you know, the world is... No, no, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: Right now, where is my, my... How do I feel in regard to that?
[SPEAKER_00]: Is there a pressure?
[SPEAKER_00]: Is there... What feeling is guiding my need to, to go and watch the news?
[SPEAKER_00]: Is it, as I said, like some genuine, whatever, reason for finding out what's happening?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or is it like, eh, I feel like I should allow myself?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you know, why?
[SPEAKER_00]: So, those ambiguous kind of ideas and stuff, that's the whole point.
[SPEAKER_00]: To bring them up and then keep pushing with questioning until it's clear why things are done the way you want them to do, the way you wanted to do them.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, that's why it's like,
[SPEAKER_00]: There's only so far you can go with, like, taking the precepts, adding extra observances, confessing them, all of that, if you're not using that for this type of, like, self-drilling, that's kind of taking you in the direction of knowing your own intentions, and then that gradually becoming an emphasized criteria for whether I should do something or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, obviously, the more questioning you invest in it, the clearer it becomes.
[SPEAKER_00]: The more, kind of, obvious your intentions and motivating factors will eventually be seen and understood.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, you wouldn't even have to sit through, like, detailed or profound or elaborate self-questioning to uncover it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, right from the start, you recognize the state of mind for what it is.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you know what intention is coming out of it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you already know whether you should follow it or not.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you know if you follow it, it's going against the training.
[SPEAKER_00]: Or if you follow it, it's not going against the training.
[SPEAKER_00]: You would know.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because training is determined by, eh... the states of mind that are free from greed, free from aversion, free from distraction, free from hindrances.
[SPEAKER_00]: And so that's the whole point.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the whole point of training and precepts, is revealing that.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's not going to be like...
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not going to be...
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, black and white, clear-cut, like, oh, this is a... not in the beginning, at least.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, you might have a reason, practical need, to check the news, which will be mixed with
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, the old habits of really, really being into news and geopolitics or whatever.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that sense will come up, that habit will pressure you and stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: But again, if you have to engage to a practical extent, you engage only to a practical extent.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then you contain that pressure, that need.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because you can't help.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, you can't help, but...
[SPEAKER_00]: Experience the elation, the pressure, the excitement of that mind that's still not fully trained.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you can contain it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, like, you know, there's, like, a kind of similar principle when...
[SPEAKER_00]: When the Buddha, on his deathbed, when Ananda, Venerable Ananda was asking different things to him, saying, you know, what should we do in regard to this?
[SPEAKER_00]: What should we do in regard to this?
[SPEAKER_00]: So, what should we do in regard to women, like as monks?
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, well, don't look at them.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, well, what if we have to look at them?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, then, don't talk to them.
[SPEAKER_00]: What if I have to talk to them?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, then, be mindful and guard your senses.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's exactly the same principle.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, don't look at yourself if you don't have to.
[SPEAKER_00]: Don't distract yourself if you don't have to, because you're just creating more work for yourself later.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, you can't always avoid it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, then you recognize, okay, when I have to, well, then I do it only to this extent.
[SPEAKER_00]: But what if, like, I have to do it longer, and my mind will really get all kind of excited about it, and all habits and patterns will come up?
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, then, be extremely mindful of that, and contain it, and just make sure you, like, do not lose the end in sight, as in...
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, yeah, my mind is excited, I need to see this through, but the moment I do, we're stopping this.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, you are still in control, so to speak.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, as the animal got excited, you can't just force them, force it to calm down, but you can make sure you don't let it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: You could still keep it in the same, in the same container.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, as I said, like, you know, things, things are not going to be black and white.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's going to take a quite a decent amount of practice before, like, the clarity is really, like, sort of,
[SPEAKER_00]: You know, you always know this is unwholesome, you always know.
[SPEAKER_00]: But until then, the animal will pressure you, the habits will come up.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, there can be like, as I said, like, so there's a factual need to say something.
[SPEAKER_00]: But the mind is angry.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, can you not say it?
[SPEAKER_00]: If that is a viable option, don't say it.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, again, living in a lay world, in particular, you will rarely have that privilege to, like, oh, I'll completely not say it and I'll say it later.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, you have to say it to some extent.
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, you make sure you don't, like, use the abusive words, obviously, you know, in like a coarse forms.
[SPEAKER_00]: But you can't help but have the mind that's already kind of wound up or something, and there's only now the window opportunity to say it and da-da-da-da-da.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, in that case, the most important thing is to not lose that sight of the whole picture.
[SPEAKER_00]: To not justify speaking out of anger.
[SPEAKER_00]: And to remain aware, okay, I'm saying this, the mind is angry, but I am aware of the difference between me saying this mindfully, with the angry mind, that I'm not letting it sort of express itself fully the way it wants.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, it's not ideal, but, like I said, that, you know, it's not impossible to train even within that environment.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, it's a lot... it's a lot harder, it's a lot stickier, it's a lot more grey areas.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's why they would refer to the household life as crowded and dusty, dirty and crowded.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you can't really... it would take a lot of effort just to kind of get to manage things rightly, let alone start to uprooting them.
[SPEAKER_00]: But that's the principle behind.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, the mind can be... mind can be wound up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Same, whether it's anger, whether it's lust, whether it's any other hindrance.
[SPEAKER_00]: And the first and foremost, it's that what I say, like, endure it on the right level, which is just another way of containing it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And when things are contained, even if you have to do something, if it's unavoidable, as it's like, you know, to look at the news or to say something and so on, it's not the same as if you justify the action almost beforehand, when you ignore the state of your mind and then just do it, because that's how you feel like it.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, containing it, even if you have to engage to some extent,
[SPEAKER_00]: As, as that, as that simile, as that example the Buddha gave, well, if you have to look, don't talk.
[SPEAKER_00]: If you have to talk, well, then be mindful until the event passes.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can literally apply that to, in regard to any hindrance, especially in the world when, when, when things are bombarded, when things are like bombarded at you and so on.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's like, you don't have to like, oh, I mustn't even feel this, this, this, this, this kind of
[SPEAKER_00]: Irritation.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, you can't help that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Animal is irritated.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it's like, it's better to recognize that and don't sort of think that I must prevent this from happening.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's more like, no, no, I must prevent anything on top of it that would be my doing.
[SPEAKER_00]: And anything on top of it that would be your doing comes always
[SPEAKER_00]: As a result of a single factor, which is not containing the animal, not containing whatever you have felt, letting it spill out, ignoring it, choosing to deal with it later.
[SPEAKER_00]: Ah, I'll do this now, and then I'll confess, and I'll do this, and so on, and justifying it like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if you don't do that, you could actually train, even with animal coming up daily,
[SPEAKER_00]: With stuff.
[SPEAKER_00]: As a matter of fact, you'll probably be having quite a lot of good material for training, if the right attitude can be maintained.
[SPEAKER_00]: The mind will be just coming up with stuff, but the context remains unchanged.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, obviously, the person has developed enough clarity, understood the purpose of the container, the knowledge of its own intentions, and recognizing that's the gateway.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because if people don't see that, then they pretty much overdo and underdo any attempted practice.
[SPEAKER_00]: So it's like, the mind comes up with irritation, and they try to get rid of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: They try to, like, choke it, kill it, get rid of it, change it, because that's bad.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then, obviously, that will fail, because you overlooked where the gateway is.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then you have the other way.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, on another occasion, the mind comes up, and then they just, like, give up.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, I'll deal with this later.
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't care.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it's like, no, you could find the middle ground.
[SPEAKER_00]: Recognize and accept that there's going to be daily instances, especially living in a lay world, of your mind coming up at you to let it out.
[SPEAKER_00]: To let it out, to say, to do things, to look at things, to engage with things, and that must have... that must never be allowed unmindfully.
[SPEAKER_00]: And initially, it feels like, oh, I must all the time watch it, but it's like... but yeah, that actually, it is easier than having to fight it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thinking that you must change the mind of anger into something else.
[SPEAKER_00]: No, you just need to contain it and don't let it express itself until it calms down.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the message you want to convey.
[SPEAKER_00]: You need... you think you need to... you need to, like, tackle the mind of lust and change it and force it to become different.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, no, that's already failing to recognize, like, what a efficient communication with the animal is.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, you think you are trying to get it to not be lustful, not be angry, but that's not the message the animal will be getting.
[SPEAKER_00]: In other words, basically, it's gonna have the opposite effect.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's gonna have, like, the effects of suppression, trying to get rid of it, this and this, which just, again, it's just gonna make the mind, the animal, even more agitable, so to speak, even more prone to those things, because now you're super sensitive about anything that can trigger it, because you still don't know where the problem or solution is.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it is on the level of containing it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It comes up, you contain it, and there will be a pressure to... oh, it would be nice if the animal is not this way.
[SPEAKER_00]: If I could change that, then I wouldn't even have to contain it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Wouldn't that be wonderful?
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's the animal tricking you into opening the door and engaging with it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Yeah, things will stop coming eventually, if the mind is tamed, but not the way a person thinks that will happen, which is, you know, the only way they can think
[SPEAKER_00]: That happening is through their own desire, through their own ideas of how it would be nice if the mind just doesn't come up.
[SPEAKER_00]: All of that means it's still falling for the same trap of craving, because of which it won't happen.
[SPEAKER_00]: For as long as the mind is not free from craving, it won't happen.
[SPEAKER_00]: The calming down of the mind won't happen.
[SPEAKER_00]: Doesn't matter how hard you concentrate, how hard you avoid, how hard you protect your environment, how purely you keep your precepts, how diligently you confess the offenses, it's not gonna happen, because the craving is still self-perpetuating inside of that animal.
[SPEAKER_00]: Having the mind that's angry or irritated, and then having to act with that state of mind,
[SPEAKER_00]: The actual, the main confining aspect of that experience is not the fact that the mind is angry.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's not the fact that you have to act.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's the fact that you still do not clearly understand the line between the two.
[SPEAKER_00]: The line between the state of mind, the extent of the mind, the extent of the pressure,
[SPEAKER_00]: And your choice to act.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's still not seen.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, there's the sense of confinement from, oh, this experience is coming, the mind is all wound up, and I have to say, and it's like overwhelming, comes from actually still kind of implicitly thinking that the whole thing is a problem.
[SPEAKER_00]: That the mind is a problem, and I don't know, it's like...
[SPEAKER_00]: So,
[SPEAKER_00]: That's unavoidable.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's going to feel like that in the beginning.
[SPEAKER_00]: But my point is, if you practice, like, uncovering of your intentions through the right questioning on the basis of precepts and training in the values of precepts, both body speech and mind, mentally, all of that, the line becomes clearer and clearer.
[SPEAKER_00]: So you could have the most violently imaginable state of mind come up.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it still won't be confining you.
[SPEAKER_00]: It still won't be overwhelming you.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's still contained, because you fully understood the extent, the range of the animal.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because that range was not understood when things, where intentions were not known, when actions were coming out of ignorant intentions, unwholesome intentions, craving and so on.
[SPEAKER_00]: But once that has been trained away from, so to speak, or trained out of you, the mind can still come up
[SPEAKER_00]: But at no point will there be any confusion about the gateway, the doorway that I talk about, and whether you, whether the animal can open it by itself, or you are responsible for it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And once you know that difference, then, as I said, the most violent imaginable state of mind, it will be equally contained, and there will be no tremble and, oh, maybe I will act out now automatically.
[SPEAKER_00]: There is no such thing.
[SPEAKER_00]: It always has to come to a choice, and that has been fully understood.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then, it doesn't matter the pressure, doesn't matter the state of mind, doesn't matter the circumstances.
[SPEAKER_00]: At that point, nothing can make you feel as confined and overwhelmed and buried, how you used to, when things were not clear.
[SPEAKER_00]: And while things back, back in the day, when things were not clear, that confinement was usually attributed to the state of mind, to the state of the... Well, imagine, like, you have a, you have a wild dog.
[SPEAKER_00]: That you never met.
[SPEAKER_00]: You'd never experienced a wild, angry dog barking at you.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you just freeze.
[SPEAKER_00]: And you don't know... Actually, snakes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Snakes are a better example of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, most people have irrational fear of snakes.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because, obviously, they never experienced or learned their behavior.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, the idea is, like, I remember in Sri Lanka, it was generally like, if you see a snake anywhere, doesn't matter how far from you,
[SPEAKER_00]: People would just kind of freeze in fear, because they would have this sense that if I do the slightest small thing wrong, that snake from like 20 meters away, that cobra that I just saw, will come after me.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, everything then becomes a problem, because you don't really understand where the actual problem is.
[SPEAKER_00]: And people would genuinely just freeze, just like be overwhelmed, frozen in fear,
[SPEAKER_00]: Because they think whatever I want to do or not do, doing is a problem, not doing is a problem, should I run, should I stay, all of that, that snake from all the way there can come and bite me and that's the end of my life.
[SPEAKER_00]: But then, obviously, you get to see it.
[SPEAKER_00]: Actually, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's not how the snake thinks.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's not how it works.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's not how its own kind of physical abilities are.
[SPEAKER_00]: You realize that's inconceivable.
[SPEAKER_00]: And now, okay, you see a snake, there is some concern, but you know the range, you know the extent.
[SPEAKER_00]: You know what you shouldn't do.
[SPEAKER_00]: I shouldn't go near it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I shouldn't go and corner it.
[SPEAKER_00]: I shouldn't go and try and grab it or things like that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But if I don't do any of those things, if I abstain from doing those things, I'm safe.
[SPEAKER_00]: Even if it comes right by me, it won't do anything to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And once that knowledge is really, like, verified, you will be unable to be frozen in fear.
[SPEAKER_00]: And same happens with the mind.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, when the mind comes up with these states,
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, person becomes aware of it, because, you know, many people wouldn't even be aware of it, they would just act out.
[SPEAKER_00]: But person becomes aware of it, but they don't know the range, they don't know the extent, they don't know where their responsibility begins and where the animal is.
[SPEAKER_00]: So then, everything feels confining, everything feels unpleasant, everything feels like a problem.
[SPEAKER_00]: Only because
[SPEAKER_00]: Well, there is still, like, lack of understanding in regard to the nature of that relationship, to put it that way.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, that's why, again, the precept only has to come first, because it doesn't matter how overwhelmed the person is, it will prevent you from going too far out in the wrong way that would genuinely aggravate the cobra, the animal.
[SPEAKER_00]: So,
[SPEAKER_00]: You stop doing that for a while, you endure the pressure on the right level, you contain it, and then exactly like, oh, there's a cobra, I'm frozen.
[SPEAKER_00]: You do it once, twice, five times, but you just, oh, it still actually haven't attacked me.
[SPEAKER_00]: I mean, okay, maybe I could just relax a bit.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's hissing, it's threatening, but you will naturally relax.
[SPEAKER_00]: When you see that, okay, okay, and then you become cautious.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, maybe... oh, okay, now, okay, now it's getting more.
[SPEAKER_00]: Okay, I won't do that.
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, look, now it doesn't mind this.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's exactly the same.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, you contain the mind and it's going to come at you, because you contained it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And it's like, oh, so what, you try to kill it now, get rid of the whole thing?
[SPEAKER_00]: Oh, if only I could just drop a bomb and get rid of that snake, everything would be perfect.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, yeah, that's not how things work.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, the mind comes up, it's like, okay, I recognize it.
[SPEAKER_00]: It would be nice.
[SPEAKER_00]: It wouldn't be nice that the...
[SPEAKER_00]: I don't even experience it yet, but that's not up to you.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it's like, the sooner you give up those naive expectations of, if only I can concentrate hard enough or do something magical so the mind will never come up, the sooner
[SPEAKER_00]: You give them up, you're closer to train rightly.
[SPEAKER_00]: It's like, no.
[SPEAKER_00]: This is a lifelong task, as it always was, by the way, even for people that don't want to train.
[SPEAKER_00]: There was always a lifelong task, putting up with your mind, following, being dragged by it, experiencing results of your actions on account of the pressures that come from the mind, paying the price, and all of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, the sooner you accept that it's actually something that it's worth investing effort in, the better.
[SPEAKER_00]: Like, the less the less damage and less work you'll have to undo later.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, the whole sense of confinement, the whole sense of fear, simply comes from insufficient understanding of, well, it doesn't matter how close this animal comes.
[SPEAKER_00]: The threat, the seeming imminent danger, you understood where the line for that is.
[SPEAKER_00]: The line is only if I act out.
[SPEAKER_00]: The line is only if I open the gate.
[SPEAKER_00]: Otherwise, it can't do anything to me.
[SPEAKER_00]: And once you know that and start sticking to it on that right level, like not giving it up, that's when the animal realizes, oh, crap, he knows it.
[SPEAKER_00]: And then it stops threatening.
[SPEAKER_00]: Because the threats work when you don't know that it's just a threat.
[SPEAKER_00]: Then, oh, and then, oh, look, it worked.
[SPEAKER_00]: I scared you.
[SPEAKER_00]: You did it.
[SPEAKER_00]: You opened the gate for me.
[SPEAKER_00]: Thank you.
[SPEAKER_00]: But, I scared him.
[SPEAKER_00]: Nope, nope, nope, nope.
[SPEAKER_00]: And he's like, oh, okay.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, it seems that he figured out.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's not opening the gate.
[SPEAKER_00]: Doesn't matter how much I threaten.
[SPEAKER_00]: In other words, he's not losing the container.
[SPEAKER_00]: He's not giving it up willingly through choice.
[SPEAKER_00]: And that's my point.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can't accidentally just, oh, lose the container.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can be distracted.
[SPEAKER_00]: You can drift away.
[SPEAKER_00]: All of that.
[SPEAKER_00]: But whenever the self-awareness reappears,
[SPEAKER_00]: When you become aware of the state of the mind and the state you're in, there and then, the choice you make determines whether you are opening the gate and releasing the container, or you're maintaining it in regard to the animal.
[SPEAKER_00]: So, you could be distracted, as I said, mindless, engaged, you have to really focus on this or that task, and... at any point through that, when self-awareness comes up, which it will have to,
[SPEAKER_00]: That's when you recognize, oh, the container... and it's like, do you then, when you recognize, when you become self-aware of the container, the state of mind and your actions, do you then, ah, it's okay, I'll carry on?
[SPEAKER_00]: Or do it's like, oh, oh, I must protect this.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's the crucial point.
[SPEAKER_00]: Not like, I must never be distracted, I must never drift off.
[SPEAKER_00]: That's impossible.
[SPEAKER_00]: But it's when the choice is presented, do you make the right one?